Alexandros Kangkelidis

Web Developer | Software Engineer

www.kangkelidis.com

★ kangkelidis@gmail.com

• London, UK

+4407462928083

github.com/alekosomegas

in Alexandros Kangkelidis



Profile

Experienced Architect/BIM Manager with a strong passion for learning, actively pursuing a career in the tech industry. Throughout my career, I have effectively collaborated with and led different teams to consistently meet deadlines and successfully deliver large and complex projects. Over the past three years, I have passionately pursued the study of Computer Science, acquiring a solid foundation in core concepts and completed a diverse range of projects.

Professional Experience

BIM Manager, Design Engine, Winchester, UK	2020 - 2022
Architectural Assistant Part 2, Pilbrow & Partners, London, UK	2019 - 2020
Architectural Assistant Part 1, Cube Design, Bournemouth, UK	2016 - 2018

Projects

 $\textbf{Car Rental and Fleet Management Software,} \ \textit{NextJS}, \textit{Javascript}, \ \textit{MongoDB} \ \ \boxdot$

Implemented the latest next and react features, such as SSR and server actions. Used chaden and tailwind for creating a responsive UI and clerk for authentication.

Rent a Car Website, NextJS, React, Tailwind

A car rental company website, allowing customers to book a car.

Taxi Management Web App, NextJS, Javascript, MongoDB ☑

Cloud-based taxi management software. It allows drivers to record their rides and track their payments. It also allows the manager to create and issue invoices to the clients, assign work to drivers, and handle payments.

Portfolio Website, NextJS, React, Tailwind ☑

Card Game, Java, LibGDX, JUnit ☑

 $2\mathsf{D}$ game based on the Greek card game Biriba. Develop in Java using the MVC pattern and LibGDX library.

Taxi Management Application, Java, JavaFX, SQLite ☑

Software used by a taxi company for management of rides, drivers, clients and fleet with automated invoices.

Attractor- Mathematics, Python, Matplotlib □

Developed for a mathematician to help her research. Calculates and plots various functions in order to find attractors.

Education

MArch Architecture, Welsh School of Architecture, 2019

Cardiff, Wales

BA Architcture, University of Portsmouth, 2016

Portsmouth, UK

Architecture and Civil Engineering, Università degli Studi Di Firenze, 2013

Florence, Italy

Courses

Mathematics for Computer Science, MIT - online

In this Discrete Mathematics course, I gained knowledge in core concepts of computer science such as discrete structures, combinatorial analytics and algorithmic thinking. I increased my problemsolving skills and mathematical maturity by applying logical reasoning and solving complex problems.

CS50AI Introduction to Artificial Intelligence, Harvard - online

I studied the theory of graph search algorithms, classification, optimization, machine learning, and large language models. I utilized machine learning libraries like NumPy, Scikit-learn, TensorFlow, and Keras to build projects focusing on game-playing engines, handwriting recognition, and machine translation.

CS61B Data structures, Berkeley - online

Through this online course, I obtained a comprehensive understanding of essential data structures, their implementation and analysis. I also learned important algorithms for sorting, path-finding and graphs traversal. Additionally, the course covered design patterns and OOP principles for software development in Java, as well as JUnit testing techniques.

Full Stack Open, University of Helsinki - online

After completing this course, I developed extensive skills in building full-stack web applications. This included utilizing React for frontend development, implementing RESTful and GraphQL web services with Node.js, and working with databases. Additionally, the course covered essential topics such as debugging applications, container technology, configuration management, CI/CD and using Git version control system.

CS61A Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs, Berkeley - online

Completed all assignments, projects, exams, and lectures available online of this course in Python. The course introduced me to high-level computer science concepts, including data abstraction, functional programming, object-oriented programming and databases.

CS50 Introduction to Computer Science, Harvard - online

Entry-level online course in C, Python, SQL, and JavaScript, teaches how to think algorithmically and solve problems efficiently.

Skills

Java | JavaFX | JUnit | Python | Ruby | C/cpp | Javascript | Typescript | CSS | Node.js React | React Native | SQL | MongoDB | GraphQL | Redux | Selenium | Cypress | REST Git | OOP | Pytest

Languages

English | Greek | Italian